# Kamlesh Kumar

(+91) 8690566377 | ■ patelkamleshpatel364@gmail.com | @kamlesh364 | @kamlesh364

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

# Summary

Final-year undergraduate student at IITRAM, awarded by Undergraduate Research Award for outstanding research work in the field of Computer Vision towards Industrial Automation. Inventor of two Indian Patents, and author of several research and two review papers. I'm keen to expand my knowledge of emerging technologies like-AI and other computer technologies. Interested in developing novel techniques and systems for realtime Image and Signal Processing applications aimed at improving human-computer interaction, with a focus on process automation using Python and Linux. Interested in learning how AI may help the healthcare sector by creating a more efficient method of addressing difficult problems and advancing the state-of-the-art in related technologies and practices.

### Education

# B.Tech. in Electrical Engineering – Institute of Infrastructure Technology Research And Management

IITRAM, India

2019 - 2023

CGPA (till 6th semester) - 8.46

- Complex Analysis and Differential Equations
- Digital Image Processing (Ongoing)
- Digital Signal Processing
- Advanced Digital Signal Processing (Ongoing).
- Computer Programming (Python, HTML/CSS/JavaScript)
- Linear Algebra with Multivariate Calculus and ODE
- Signals and Systems
- Digital Systems
- · Probability and Random Processes
- Autonomous Navigation

# **Experience**

# **Industrial Work Experience**

#### Machine Learning Engineering, Intern – Full Time (Paid)

Remote

SkyLark Labs Pvt. Lt., San Francisco, California, United States of America

- Responsibilities- ML/DL model development, writing algorithms for object detection and tracking using computer vision.
- Contributing to numerous ITMS projects for product development and PoCs.

#### Computer Vision Developer – Part Time (Paid)

AZTEC Fluids and Machinery Pvt. Lt.

Aug. 2021 - Oct. 2021 Ahmedabad, India

December, 2022 - Present

- · Worked on projects related to industrial automation.
- Automated conveyor lines for autonomous packaging of various plumbing objects.
- · Designed an overall service architecture and pipelines of the system to count and collect objects for faster productions of homogenous items, along with real-time inspection.

#### Image Processing and Computer Vision Intern – Full Time (Paid)

Institute of Infrastructure Technology Research And Management

May. 2021 - July.2021 Ahmedabad, India

- Worked on several research studies related to Image Processing and Computer Vision.
- Designed algorithms for operations related to Real-Time image processing.

### Deep Learning Intern - Full Time

Institute of Infrastructure Technology Research And Management

May. 2022 - July. 2022 Ahmedabad, India

- Several researches were conducted on Deep Learning and its applications for Image and Signal Processing.
- Designed and developed Deep Neural Networks using Python3 and TensorFlow2 for instance segmentations and object detection.

#### **AMAZON ML Summer School**

July. 2022

Online

 Integrated learning program for students focused on ML topics like-Supervised Learning, Deep Neural Networks, Dimensionality Reduction, Unsupervised Learning, Probabilistic Graphical Models, Sequential Learning, Causal Inference and Reinforcement Learning.

# Computer Vision Engineer – Full Time internship offer letter – School of International Biodesign (Paid)

· Stanford University, USA.

· QUT, Australia

In collaboration with -

Amazon

· Hiroshima University, Japan

- Tottori University, Japan
- · Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi
- All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Delhi.

#### **Research Work Experience**

- 1. Inventor of "Method And System Of Counting And Collecting Objects In Packaging Automation **Platform" – Indian Patent**, Granted (Indian Patent No. 408712).
- 2. Machine Vision Based System For Jewellery Artwork And Method Thereof Indian Patent, Filled.
- 3. Pulse oximetry SpO<sub>2</sub> signal for automated identification of sleep apnea: A review and future trends doi: 10.1088/1361-6579/ac98f0.
- 4. A real Time Object Counting and Collecting for Industrial Automation Process using Machine Vision -Provisionally accepted by IEEE sensors journal.

- 5. Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning based interventions in Medical Infrastructure: A Review and Future Trends —Published- MDPI Healthcare Journal- doi: 10.3390/healthcare11020207.
- **6. Modified Mask-RCNN architecture for tooth segmentation in panoramic x-rays** Under Review.
- 7. Insomnia Detection using single channel EEG-signal with Continuous Wavelet Transform and Convolutional Neural Network— Under Review.

# **Projects**

## **Smart CBCT analysis Using Deep Learning**

November, 2021-Ongoing

- Analyzing CBCT scans for detection of various diseases and defects in bones.
- Developing a web-based commercial platform to provide the solution as SAS.

#### Warehouse management system (Paid Project)

August, 2022-October, 2022

- Automation of assembly lines using Vision sensors and Image processing for segregating products based on the information extracted from QR-Codes.
- Real-time database management system for recording and monitoring orders, packaging, inventory, and dispatch.

# **Bone Tumor Detection Using Deep Learning**

May,2022

• Developed a solutions for Cancer Research Scientists to analyze bone x-rays and plan the surgeries for Cancer Removal.

#### **Real-time Object Detector and Counter (Paid Project)**

July, 2021-October, 2021

• A completely autonomous solution that automates product counting and packing, using vision based inspection lines.

#### **Automated Brain Tumor Detection**

Iune.2022

· Analyzed MRI scans for detection of Cancerous tumors in human brain through deep learning and image processing.

#### Plant Health Prediction system using Sensor fusion and Machine Learning

July,2022

Water and Soil ingredient requirement prediction using real-time analysis of soil and leaf color.

#### **Additional Courses and Certifications**

AI for Medical Diagnosis
 Advanced Computer Vision with TensorFlow
 DeepLearning.ai TensorFlow Developer
 Introduction to Self-Driving-Cars by University of Toronto
 Deep-learning specialization by DeepLearning.ai
 Python for Data Science, AI & Development
 June, 2021
 April, 2021
 March, 2021
 October, 2021

Data Science MethodologyTools for Data Science

October, 2021

Introduction to MATLAB Programming by Vanderbilt University

September, 2021 October, 2020

Google IT Automation professional Certificate

August, 2020 August, 2020

Introduction to Internet of Things and Embedded systems by University of California, Irvine
Interfacing with Arduino by University of California, Irvine

August, 2020

• The Arduino Platform and C Programming by University of California, Irvine

August,2020

Machine Learning by Stanford University

July, 2020

Mathematics for Machine Learning by Imperial College London

June. 2020

Internet of Things and Machine Learning by Bolt IoT

April, 2020

# **Technical Skills**

Python, TensorFlow, OpenCV, PyQt5, HTML/CSS/JS, ReactJS, ReactNative, AZURE, Flask, Unix/Linux, ROS, MATLAB

# **Position of Responsibility**

Student Placement Coordinator, Placement Cell - IITRAM

Sept. 2021 - Present

Secretory, Robotics and Aeromodelling Club - IITRAM

July. 2021 - Present

Organizing Committee Member, TEDxIITRAM - IITRAM

April. 2022

# **Standardized Test Scores**

- Graduate Record Examination(GRE) 313/340 (168/170- Quantitative Reasoning)
- International English Listening Teaching and Speaking, Examination(IELTS) 7.5 Bands

# **Honors and Awards**

- **Certificate of Merit** eYantra Robotic Competition-2021, Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay.
- **Funds Raised** approx. INR. 2,00,000 were raised through Student Startup and Innovation Policy for PoC development.
- **Undergraduate Research Award-** Honored by the top research award at Junior level for presenting novel research work.